Saravjeet Singh Chaggar

ETL Consultant

+91-9975568427 | +91-7974442440 | saravjeet.singh@hotmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/schaggar

Profile

Data professional with **12 years** of strong experience in building, maintaining and testing Enterprise Data warehouse/Data marts across multiple domains to drive advance analytics for business decisions. Experience in handling small to medium teams, additionally, gained expertise working as individual contributor.

Open to any opportunities related to Data and Analytics. Like to work closely with customer, understand their requirements, derive and develop optimal solutions and applications by applying the skills gained over the years which help business users to make qualitative decisions.

Experience

ETL CONSULTANT | TERADATA INDIA PVT. LTD. | FEB 2014 - PRESENT

- ETL design, development and implementation of large data warehousing projects.
- · Experience in Semantic Layer Design and Development.
- · Automation and performance optimization of the ETL jobs
- · Parsing Semi-structured data (XML) using Teradata Vantage NewSQL engine.
- · Experience in handling teams and project related activities.
- · Sound knowledge GCFR (Global Control Framework Repository A Teradata Product) tool.
- · Post deployment production support and resolution.
- · SQL Performance tuning and optimization.
- Experience in working in Agile development environments.
- Unit, Integration and Operational Testing.
- · Responsible for creating and maintaining the SMX [Source to Target mappings] and other project deliverables.
- UAT support (output investigations)
- · SQL scripting (stored procedures, DDLs)
- · Knowledge of Teradata Logical Models: mLDM, fsLDM, cLDM.

DWBI TEST CONSULTANT | COGNIZANT TECHNOLOGIES PVT. LTD. | APRIL 2011 - NOVEMBER 2013

- Test Documentation [System Integration Test Cases, Test Plan and Strategy Document]
- · Hands on experience in testing Cognos, Micro strategy, OBIEE and SAP BO reports.
- · Experience in using HUE, Presto and Spark while working on Bigdata testing.
- · Tested MDM (Master Data Management) projects.
- Experience in writing, reviewing and executing test cases.
- · Experience in Data Migration Testing.
- Experience in handling teams and project related activities.
- Excellent interpersonal, communication and documentation skills.
- · Well-known with all the stages of Defect Tracking Life Cycle (DTLC).
- · Hands on experience in generating scripts (SQL) for functionality testing.

DWBI TEST ANALYST | HSBC | APRIL 2008 - APRIL 2011

- Requirement understanding and converting them into test cases and test scenarios.
- Writing complex test SQLs for ETL/BI test cases.
- · Status reporting and Defect Management.
- · Attending and managing defect triage calls.

· Update stakeholders about the project status and issues.

Skills

- · ETL (Extract, Transform and Load)
- · SQL
- · Teradata
- · Talend
- Informatica
- · HDFS
- · Agile

- · Kafka
- · No SQL Databases (Mongo DB)
- · Unix
- · Perl
- · Python
- · ETL/BI Testing

Roles Played

- · ETL Developer
- · Test Manager
- · Data Engineer
- · ETL/BI Tester
- · Individual contributor

- · Delivery Lead
- · Test Coordinator
- · Data Analyst
- · Senior Technical Lead

Domains

- · Manufacturing and Logistics
- · Banking and Financial Services

- Insurance
- · Healthcare

Clients

- · HSBC
- · BMW, Germany
- · KPN, Netherlands
- · Vocalink, UK
- · Saudi Telecom
- · Direct Line Group
- · Volvo, Sweden Sainsbury, UK

Interest Area

- · Information Management
- · Business Intelligence
- · Cloud
- · Artificial Intelligence

- · Machine Learning
- · Python
- · Open-Source

Types of Data

- · Structured
- · Semi-Structured XML/JSON

Certifications

· Teradata 14 Certified Professional

- Diploma in Software Testing
- Pursuing AWS Solution Architect 2020

Strengths

- · Quick Learner
- Smart Worker
- Dedication
- · Commitment

Education

Shri Shankaracharya College of Engineering and Technology Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Computer Science Engineering (2003-2007)

Honors and Awards

- **Quarterly Award Q2 2019** (Teradata Sep 2019) Received this award for delivering quality products/applications to the customer.
- **BMW Miniature (Prototype)** from BMW Germany for Excellent and timely delivery of the application (Teradata July 2017)
- · Certificate from **Volvo for Excellent Project Delivery** (Teradata Jun 2014) Received the certificate for the successful completion of MCA2 (Connected Cars Project) release while working with client Volvo (Sweden).
- **Certificate of Appreciation** from Saudi Telecom Company (Riyadh, Saudi Arabia, Onsite Assignment) on the successful completion and implementation of the NNP project.
- **Quarterly Award (Q2)** @ Teradata (Teradata Jun 2014) Received the below comments from the higher management:
 - Dedication
 - Picked up things so quickly as SPOC.

Project Roles, Experience and Delivery

Project 1:

10,0001	
Project Title	AIP [Agile Information Platform]
Duration	06/07/2017- till date
Project Location	Munich, Germany
Work Location	Pune, India
Tools and Technologies	Teradata SQL, TPT, BTEQ, Perl, Unix, XML,
	SLJM, HPALM
Client	BMW
Domain	Manufacturing and Logistics

Project Overview:

BMW Agile Information Platform (AIP) intension is to establish a full end-to-end transparency for the complete supply chain incl. alerting/early warning reporting. In order to achieve this goal, it is necessary to collect and integrate data about the whole Order to Delivery (OtD) process.

The AIP will be able to provide analytics/reporting/alerting/simulation to the BMW business units. Currently the supply chains from the packing plants in Germany (Leipzig and Neutraubling) to different BMW units. Focus of the AIP is currently of the supply chain from the packing plant to the plants in Spartanburg (US), Rosslyn (ZA) and the plants Tiexi and Dadong in China.

Responsibilities:

- · Senior Technical Lead [Lead Developer].
- · Involved in requirement gathering.
- · Responsible for Design and Development and Testing of the Interfaces feeding data to AIP.
- · Code deployment to higher environments.
- Ensuring that the relevant documentation is updated and maintained in SVN.
- · Responsible for analysis and resolution of the issues raised by the UAT team.
- · Unit testing, System Integration Testing and supporting UAT.
- · Responsible for creating Test Strategy and Test Planning documents.
- Other task includes Test Data creation, Test Scenario identification, Test case preparation, Test Execution, Defect management and Status reporting.
- · Communicating and reporting the status of the project with project stakeholders for the assigned module.
- · Understand and implement project scope within defined timelines.
- · Deliver on time with expected quality standards.
- · Responsible for Test environment setup.
- Test data is available and setup correctly for test execution.
- · Identify potential risks and suggest mitigation plan.
- · Responsible for status reporting and test metrics reporting.
- · Responsible for defect management.

Project 2:

10,000 = 1	
Project Title	Best for Customer (B4C)
Duration	23/08/2015-31/07/2016
Project Location	London
Work Location	Bromley, London, UK (Onsite)
Tools and Technologies	Informatica, Teradata, HP ALM
Client	Direct Line Group (DLG)
Domain	Insurance

Project Overview:

The business objective is to provide the Direct Line Group with an improved capability to deliver marketing campaigns to households and individuals across several channels (e.g., direct mail, telemarketing, email and SMS).

This project will implement the CIM solution as part of the Multi-Channel Campaign Management (MCCM) work stream within the Best for Customer program.

Under the same objective, Teradata is in the process of developing a semantic layer strategy to use the integrated data layer for CIM business users. The solution specified in this document is a high-level design overview for the new CIM platform solution.

Responsibilities:

- Working as Onsite Test Coordinator for Best for Customer project.
- Responsible for Creating Test Strategy and Test Planning documents.
- Other task includes Test Data creation, Test Scenario identification, Test case preparation, Test Execution, Defect management and Status reporting.
- Responsible for ETL/DW Testing
- Communicating and reporting the status of the project with project stakeholders for the assigned module.
- Understand and implement project scope within defined timelines.
- Deliver on time with expected quality standards.
- Responsible for Test environment setup.
- Test data is available and setup correctly for test execution.

- Identify potential risks and suggest mitigation plan.
- Ensure that the test project documentation is complete and updated.
- Responsible for status reporting and test metrics reporting.
- Responsible for defect management.

Project 3:

Project Title	Project Data Insight (PDI) - Tier 1
Duration	25/04/2014- 04/07/2015
Project Location	London
Work Location	Rickmansworth, London, UK
Tools and Technologies	Oracle Data Integrator, GCFR (Global
	Control Framework) Teradata, Tivoli, HP
	ALM
Client	Vocalink
Domain	Financial Services

Project Overview:

The initial scope of the PDI program is to build a Data Platform to support analytics capability for the development of future Data Products (as agreed at Steer Co). Provide Access to data in the data warehouse (this includes analytics software access)

The central component to this is the Teradata data warehouse appliance – which will manage and store data extracts from existing systems (initially Bacs2 and FPS), as well as data extracts from new interfaces.

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for Test Planning, Test Data creation, Test Scenario identification, Test case preparation, Test Execution, Defect management and Status reporting.
- Responsible for ETL/DW Testing
- Responsible for End to End testing through Tivoli.
- Communicating and reporting the status of the project with project stakeholders for the assigned module.
- Understand and implement project scope within defined timelines.
- Deliver on time with expected quality standards.
- Co-ordinate with Test manager for issues resolution.
- Conduct test design walk through, requirement analysis and reviews.
- Ensure that test environment is available and setup correctly for test execution.
- Ensure test data is available and setup correctly for test execution.
- Identify potential risks and suggest mitigation plan.
- Ensure that the test project documentation is complete and updated.
- Responsible for status reporting and test metrics reporting.
- Responsible for defect management.

Project 4:

<u> </u>	
Project Title	New Numbering Plan (NNP)
Duration	01/03/2013-01/05/2013
Project Location	Saudi Arabia, Riyadh
Work Location	Saudi Arabia, Riyadh (Onsite)
Tools and Technologies	SQL, Teradata Multiload, fastload,
	fastexport scripts, Teradata cLDM,
	Datastage, C programs, HP ALM
Client	Saudi Telcom Company
Domain	Telecom

Project Overview:

STC will be revising the current Land Line numbering with a New Numbering Plan (NNP), to help increase the range/limit of the Land Line numbers. According to this change STC will be adding the digit ('1') to the land line numbers across the Kingdom. This change will allow STC number series to expand for a longer range of numbers.

For instance, based on this change a current number like '01 1234567' will be revised to '011 1234567'.

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for Test Planning, Test Data creation, Test Scenario identification, Test case preparation, Test Execution, Defect management and Status reporting.
- Responsible for ETL (Data stage jobs) and report testing (BO reports)
- Code deployment to test environment.
- Responsible for End to End testing.
- Managing the testing activities under the agile development environment.
- Communicating and reporting the status of the project with project stakeholders for the assigned module.
- Allocating and monitoring project related work assigned to the team members.
- Understand and implement project scope within defined timelines.
- Monitor and guide the team in project execution.
- Deliver on time with expected quality standards.
- Co-ordinate with Test manager for issues resolution.
- Conduct test design walk through, requirement analysis and reviews.
- Ensure that test environment is available and setup correctly for test execution.
- Ensure test data is available and setup correctly for test execution.
- Identify potential risks and suggest mitigation plan.
- Ensure that the test project documentation is complete and updated.
- Responsible for status reporting and test metrics reporting.
- Responsible for defect management.
- Implement test process improvements resulting from lessons learnt.

Project 5:

TOJECTOI	
Project Title	Allergan Insights System
Duration	06/02/2017- 01/02/2018
Project Location	USA
Work Location	ZS Associates (Pune, India), Onsite
Tools and Technologies	ZS Edge, Bigdata, HUE, Presto, Spark, Micro
	strategy
Client	Allergan
Domain	Healthcare

Project Overview:

The primary objective of foundational data warehouse system is to load, process and integrate various data sources across sales and marketing subject areas. The data outputs of the system will be provided to downstream applications that require raw and aligned / credited sales data on a weekly or monthly basis. The data warehouse will also provide the necessary data for the reporting data mart. The system should address current business needs and be flexible to address future business needs without significant change.

Responsibilities:

- Working as Test Consultant for Allergan.
- Test Scenario identification, Test case preparation, Test Execution, Defect management and Status reporting.
- Responsible for ETL Testing.
- Communicating and reporting the status of the project with project stakeholders for the assigned module.
- Understand and implement project scope within defined timelines.
- Deliver on time with expected quality standards.
- Responsible for Test environment setup.
- Test data is available and setup correctly for test execution.
- Identify potential risks and suggest mitigation plan.
- Ensure that the test project documentation is complete and updated.
- Responsible for status reporting and test metrics reporting.
- Responsible for defect management.

Project 6:

Project Title	Gilead ARC Japan DWH Implementation
Duration	01/12/2016- 03/02/2017
Project Location	Japan
Work Location	ZS Associates (Pune, India), Onsite
Tools and Technologies	Informatica, Oracle, Automic (UC4), HP ALM
Client	Gilead
Domain	Healthcare

Project Overview:

The purpose of the project is to create a new instance of the data management layer of the ARC (Analytical Reporting Capabilities) solution implemented in EMEA and Asia for Gilead Japan. This will involve customizing the ARC data management components for EMEA and reconfiguring for Gilead K.K. ("Gilead Japan").

Responsibilities:

- Worked as Test Lead for Gilead Japan ARC Implementation.
- Responsible for Creating RTM, Test Strategy, Test Planning and Test end report documents.
- Other task includes Test Data creation, Test Scenario identification, Test case preparation, Test Execution, Defect management and Status reporting.
- Responsible for (ETL Testing) End to End testing.
- Actively participated in supporting UAT.
- Responsible for finding the root cause of the defects and helped the development team in fixing them as well during SIT and UAT phases.
- Communicating and reporting the status of the project with project stakeholders for the assigned module.
- Understand and implement project scope within defined timelines.
- Deliver on time with expected quality standards.
- Responsible for Test environment setup.
- Test data is available and setup correctly for test execution.
- Identify potential risks and suggest mitigation plan.
- Ensure that the test project documentation is complete and updated.
- Responsible for status reporting and test metrics reporting.
- Responsible for defect management.

Project 6:

Project Title	KPN BI Innovation
Duration	01/07/2011-01/03/2013

Project Location	Netherlands
Work Location	Pune, India
Tools and Technologies	Teradata cLDM, Informatica, UC4
Client	KPN
Domain	Telecom

Project Overview:

KPN BI Innovation is the Teradata data warehouse application which has been created to facilitate the users to get the details of the customers, offerings, billings and revenue etc through a single and common data warehouse which will hold the data for all the products like Mobile, fixed line etc.

IWH is the data source from where data is coming in file format. This data then processed through ETL Informatica to transform it as per the business rule given. Transformed data is getting loaded into Teradata data warehouse. Once the data is in Teradata (cLDM) EDW then it is further processed through ODS system to capture business information at subscription and product level.

The ODS data further processed through Scorecard engine to calculate measure information, which is directly used by business users for their strategic decision.

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for Test Planning.
- Responsible for report testing (OBIEE reports) which are presented to business/end users.
- Responsible for end to end schedule testing through scheduling tool UC4.
- Detailed test planning, allocation and monitoring project related work assigned to the team members.
- Understand and implement project scope within defined timelines.
- Monitor and guide the team in project execution.
- Responsible for adherence to organizational processes.
- Deliver on time with expected quality standards.
- Co-ordinate with Test manager for issues resolution.
- Conduct test design walk through, requirement analysis and reviews.
- Responsible for test traceability matrix.
- Ensure that test environment is available and setup correctly for test execution.
- Ensure test data is available and setup correctly for test execution.
- Identify potential risks and suggest mitigation plan.
- Ensure that the test project documentation is complete and updated.
- Responsible for status reporting and test metrics reporting.
- Responsible for defect management.
- Implement test process improvements resulting from lessons learnt.

Project 7:

Project Title	Volvo Connected Cars
Duration	10/02/2014- 10/02/2015
Project Location	London
Work Location	Pune, India
Tools and Technologies	Informatica, Teradata, HP ALM
Client	Volvo, Sweden
Domain	Manufacturing

Responsibilities:

- Working as Offshore Test Lead for Volvo.
- Responsible for Creating Test Strategy and Test Planning documents.

- Other task includes Test Data creation, Test Scenario identification, Test case preparation, Test Execution, Defect management and Status reporting.
- Responsible for ETL/DW Testing
- Communicating and reporting the status of the project with project stakeholders for the assigned module.
- Understand and implement project scope within defined timelines.
- Deliver on time with expected quality standards.
- Responsible for Test environment setup.
- Test data is available and setup correctly for test execution.
- Identify potential risks and suggest mitigation plan.
- Ensure that the test project documentation is complete and updated.
- Responsible for status reporting and test metrics reporting.
- Responsible for defect management.

Personal Particulars

Current Location Pune

Date of Birth 16th December 1984

Nationality Indian Passport H2015454

Permanent Address H 268, Model town, P.O. Nehru nagar. Bhilai, Chattisgarh

Marital Status Married

Email ID <u>saravjeet.singh@hotmail.com</u>